Toggle navigation [Paprika](http://www.paprikaapp.com/)

    * DESKTOP
    
    * MOBILE

### Privacy Policy

Last Modified: June 28, 2019

**Introduction**

Hindsight Labs LLC (”**Company**” or “**We**”) respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy.

This policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the website [www.paprikaapp.com](http://www.paprikaapp.com/) (our “**Website**”), or download and use the Paprika Recipe Manager mobile and desktop applications (collectively the Websites and applications, including all related documentation, are the “**Software**”), and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing that information.

This policy applies to information we collect:

* On this Website.
* In email, text, and other electronic messages between you and this Website.
* Through mobile and desktop applications you download from this Website or from third-party app stores, which provide dedicated non-browser-based interaction between you and this Website.

It does not apply to information collected by:

* Us offline or through any other means, including on any other website operated by Company or any third party; or
* Any third party, including through any application or content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from or through the Software.

Please read this policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use our Software. By accessing or using this Software, you agree to this privacy policy. This policy may change from time to time (see Changes to Our Privacy Policy). Your continued use of this Software after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the policy periodically for updates.

* * *

**Children Under the Age of 16**

Our Software is not intended for children under 16 years of age. No one under age 16 may provide any information to the Software. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If you are under 16, do not use or provide any information to the Software or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 16 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 16, please contact us at contact@paprikaapp.com.

* * *

**Information We Collect About You and How We Collect It**

We collect several types of information from and about users of our Software, including information:

* By which you may be personally identified, such as name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, or any other identifier by which you may be contacted online or offline (”personal information”);
* That is about you but individually does not identify you, such as user data entered into the Software; and/or
* About your internet connection, the equipment you use to access our Software, and usage details.

We collect this information:

* Directly from you when you provide it to us.
* Automatically when you use the Software. Information collected automatically may include usage details, IP addresses, and information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies.
* From third parties, for example, our business partners.

* * *

**Information You Provide to Us**

The information we collect on or through our Software may include:

* Information you directly enter into our Software, such as: recipes, grocery lists, meal plans, menus, bookmarks, and any other data.
* Information you provide when you register an account, such as: your email address and password.
* Information you provide when you report a problem with our Software, such as: crash logs or screenshots.
* Records and copies of your correspondence (including email addresses), if you contact us.
* Details of transactions you carry out through our Website and of the fulfillment of your orders. You may be required to provide financial information before placing an order through our Website. We do not store financial information after your order is processed.

You also may provide information to be transmitted to other users of the Software or third parties (collectively, “User Contributions”). Your User Contributions are posted and transmitted to others at your own risk. Additionally, we cannot control the actions of third parties with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that your User Contributions will not be viewed by unauthorized persons.

* * *

**Information We Collect Through Automatic Data Collection Technologies**

As you download, access, use, or navigate through and interact with our Software, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect certain information about your equipment, browsing actions, and patterns, including:

* Details of your interactions with our Software, including traffic data, logs, and other communication data and the resources that you access and use in the Software.
* Information about your device and internet connection, including the device’s unique device identifier, IP address, operating system, browser type, and mobile network information.
* Crash logs automatically generated if the Software crashes.
* This Software also may access metadata and other information associated with other files stored on your device. This may include, for example, photographs.
* This Software does not collect real-time information about the location of your device.

The information we collect automatically is only statistical data and does not include personal information, but we may maintain it or associate it with personal information we collect in other ways or receive from third parties. It helps us to improve our Software and to deliver a better and more personalized service, including by enabling us to:

* Estimate our audience size and usage patterns.
* Store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Software according to your individual interests.
* Recognize you when you return to our Software.

The technologies we use for this automatic data collection may include:

* Cookies (or browser cookies). A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our Website. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system may issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Website.
* Web Beacons. Pages of our Website and our e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that permit the Company, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an email and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity).

We do not collect personal information automatically, but we may tie this information to personal information about you that we collect from other sources or you provide to us.

* * *

**Third-Party Information Collection**

When you use the App or its content, certain third parties may use automatic information collection technologies to collect information about you or your device. These third parties may include:

* Analytics companies.
* Your device manufacturer.
* Your mobile service provider.
* Automated crash reporting services.

These third parties may use tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use this app. The information they collect may be associated with your personal information or they may collect information, including personal information, about your online activities over time and across different websites, apps, and other online services websites. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based (behavioral) advertising or other targeted content. We do not control these third parties’ tracking technologies or how they may be used. If you have any questions about an advertisement or other targeted content, you should contact the responsible provider directly. For information about how you can opt out of receiving targeted advertising from many providers, see Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information.

* * *

**How We Use Your Information**

We use information that we collect about you or that you provide to us, including any personal information:

* To present our Software and its contents to you.
* To provide you with information, products, or services that you request from us.
* To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it.
* To provide you with notices about your account.
* To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection.
* To notify you about changes to our Software or any products or services we offer or provide though it.
* To recognize you when you use the Software.
* In any other way we may describe when you provide the information.
* To contact you to request more information regarding crash reports you have submitted, if you have provided an email address with the crash report.
* For any other purpose with your consent.

* * *

**Disclosure of Your Information**

We may disclose aggregated information about our users, and information that does not identify any individual, without restriction. We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this privacy policy:

* To our subsidiaries and affiliates.
* To contractors, service providers, and other third parties we use to support our business and who are bound by contractual obligations to keep personal information confidential and use it only for the purposes for which we disclose it to them.
* To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of Hindsight Labs LLC’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by Hindsight Labs LLC about our Software users is among the assets transferred.
* To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it. For example, if you give us an email address to use the “email a friend” feature of our Software, we will transmit the contents of that email and your email address to the recipients.
* For any other purpose disclosed by us when you provide the information.
* With your consent.

We may also disclose your personal information:

* To comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request.
* To enforce or apply our terms of use ([www.paprikaapp.com/terms](http://www.paprikaapp.com/terms/)) and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes.
* If we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of Hindsight Labs LLC, our customers, or others.

* * *

**Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information:

* Tracking Technologies and Advertising. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.
* Promotional Offers from the Company. If you do not wish to have your email address used by the Company to promote our own products or services, you can opt-out by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any email we send.

We do not control third parties’ collection or use of your information to serve interest-based advertising. However these third parties may provide you with ways to choose not to have your information collected or used in this way. You can opt out of receiving targeted ads from members of the Network Advertising Initiative (”NAI”) on the NAI’s website.

* * *

**Accessing and Correcting Your Information**

You can review and change your personal information by logging into the Software and visiting your account profile page. You may also send us an email at contact@paprikaapp.com to request access to, correct or delete any personal information that you have provided to us. We cannot delete your personal information except by also deleting your user account. We may not accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect. Proper access and use of information provided on the Software, including User Contributions, is governed by our terms of use ([www.paprikaapp.com/terms](http://www.paprikaapp.com/terms/)).

* * *

**Data Security**

We have implemented measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers behind firewalls. Any payment transactions or other transmissions of sensitive data will be encrypted using SSL technology.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our Software, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet and mobile platforms is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted through our Software. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures we provide.

* * *

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

It is our policy to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page. If we make material changes to how we treat our users’ personal information, we will notify you through a notice on the Website home page. The date the privacy policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date active and deliverable email address for you, and for periodically visiting our Website and this privacy policy to check for any changes.

* * *

**Contact Information**

To ask questions or comment about this privacy policy and our privacy practices, contact us at: contact@paprikaapp.com

* * *

[Privacy](http://www.paprikaapp.com/privacy/) • [Terms](http://www.paprikaapp.com/terms/) • Designed and developed by Hindsight Labs LLC
